Mikhail Jackson

(206) 883-6436 l <u>jacksm1221@gmail.com</u> linkedin.com/in/mikhail-jackson12 l github.com/zhaza

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Innovative software engineer with 460+ training hours and experience developing full stack Java applications as well as programming skills necessary to become a web developer. Backed by 5+ years of transferable financial, analytical, and problem-solving skills as well as working in fast-paced teams with a focus on growth mindsets and implementing solutions by using creative software engineering principles.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

W3Schools Javascript Certification (in progress; expected date of completion 07/2022) Udemy SQL Certification (12/2021)

- Java
- Python
- SQL
- MongoDB
- HTML
- CSS

- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- React
- Node
- REST API's
- Git

- Spring Boot
- Spring Data JPA
- Spring Security (JWT)
- Unit Testing (JUnit, Mockito)
- Object-oriented Programming
- Dependencies Injection

EXPERIENCE

Generation USA Jr Full Stack Developer Program I Washington, D.C I Mar 2022 - July 2022 Participating in a **16**-week, **460+** hour Junior Full Stack Java Developer program that emphasizes handson practical application, learning and adopting the technologies involved in creating full stack web applications with Java using Spring Boot Framework, HTML5, CSS3, and implementing basic unit tests and deploying the application to Heroku.

AltraVue Capital I Bellevue, WA I Aug 2021 - Oct 2021 *Operations Associate Intern*

- Built an automated data mining and modeling system using algorithms in Power Query to decrease COO's manual workload by +50%, then issued trainings and documentation.
- Developed new, recurring client decks through ideation using a hybrid of Microsoft Products to efficiently decrease Leadership's report turnaround time to Client from 3 days to 1 hour.
- Integrated a visually impactful, interactive dashboard in Power Pivot for instantaneous updates of performance data which eliminated turnaround time, allowing Leadership's review on firm's timeline.
- Maintained weekly/monthly reporting documents to ensure \$1B fund allocation.

Highline Public Schools | Burien, WA | Feb 2018 - Feb 2021

Business Services Partner

- Promoted from Associated Student Body (ASB) Coordinator after a year by strong communication in cross-cooperative team environments, saving **75%** of time in data entry at year-end reporting.
- Delivered collaborative internal audits on time at +30 schools and +15 departments with 100% compliance of internal and industry best practices, resulting in 3 years of passed external audits.
- Administered onboarding to train all school/department administrators, and acted as a primary internal resource for all internal/external teams on best practices, procedures, and policies.
- Improved processes by implementing new technologies, services, and products to support and save managers 15% of workload time during data processing. (i.e., Forecast 5, FamilyID, InTouch Lite)

EDUCATION

Western Washington University | Bellingham, WA | July 2017 Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration, Finance